# Vish Dev

#### vishdev.co@gmail.com

## **Profile Summary**

Dedicated professional with over 6 years of IT experience within the fields of web application development, database administration, data backup and recovery. Currently working as a full-stack web developer specializing in Ruby on Rails. Continually recognized for hard work, integrity and client satisfaction.

#### **Qualifications and Skills**

- · Create highly interactive modern applications and websites.
- Extensive experience building Ruby on Rails and WordPress websites.
- · Experience with all stages of the development cycle for dynamic web projects.
- · Strong experience in using Ruby on Rails in a UNIX/LINUX environment.
- Experience in Oracle database administration including installation, maintenance, tuning and upgrades. Oracle backup and recovery using RMAN, hot-cold backup, export-import and Data Pump.
- Past experience in data backup, recovery with EMC Networker, IBM Tivoli Storage Manager (TSM).

## **Experience**

### Full Stack Ruby on Rails Engineer, Fitroom Inc/GoFind, Sep 2016 - Current

- Develop web application and implement user interface using Ruby on Rails, CSS, HTML5,
  JavaScript, JQuery in collaborative team environment.
- · Involved in deployment and maintaining of the application in cloud using MS Azure's Linux Virtual Machines.
- Responsible for creating categories, updating databases using migrations and regularly monitoring them.
- Involved in handling code reviews and bug fixes.
- Involved in working with databases regularly whenever a new category gets created.
- · Work on developing and designing model, view and controller of the application.
- Work with Devise and Omniauth gems for user authentication and social login.
- · Manage code versioning with GitHub.

#### Ruby on Rails Developer, Independent Contractor, Aug 2014 - Sep 2016

- Developed business and personal websites, e-commerce, social media and e-learning platforms.
- · Consulted with clients on website strategy including functionality and design.
- Gathered requirements from clients and identified key features for making their websites profitable and appealing to visitors.
- Analyzed competitor websites, determined content and communicated progress with clients throughout project timeline.
- · Used the approach of mobile first responsive design for all projects.
- Optimized website performance using latest technologies and industry best practices.

#### Backup and Recovery Storage Support Specialist, IBM, Jul 2012 - Aug 2014

- · Created and managed all backup schedules, backup policies that controlled data retention and migration.
- Coordinated and assisted in problem determination and resolution for backup and restore issues.
- Participated in the design, testing, and ongoing support of the Disaster Recovery Planwith regard to Storage Backups and Restores.
- Monitored and tracked backup performance and capacity. Predicted and planed for future capacity requirements.
- Established, documented, reviewed, and maintained standards and procedures for Tivoli Storage Manager and storage backup management.

#### Backup Administrator, Cap Gemini, Jan 2011 - July 2012

- · Responsible for installing networker clients.
- Ensured reliable backups to meet operational and data recovery requirements.
- · Implemented and administered a backup and restore system.
- Documented backup and recovery process and strategy.
- · Read backup logs to verify a successful backup and restore process.
- Monitored the backup and restore process and data growth projections.
- · Monthly offline backups and location of data to be backedup.

### **Technical Skills**

Development: Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, HTML5, CSS, XML, WordPress, JavaScript, jQuery, Git,

Bitbucket, GitHub, Heroku, AWS, Azure

Operating Systems: Linux, Mac OS X, MS Windows

Language & Database: Ruby, SQL, PL/SQL, Oracle, SQLite, MySQL

**Ruby Gems:** Device, Paperclip, Bootstrap-sass, country\_select, sunspot\_rails, sunspot\_solr, activeadmin, acts\_as\_votable & commentable, FriendlyId, Geocoder, Jquery-rails, Byebug, Minitest, Will Paginate,

CanCan, RSpec etc.

#### **Education**

**Database, Data Analytics and Web Development,** University of California Santa Cruz **Bachelor in Computer Science with a minor in Economics,** Garhwal University